[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
And now, we have the complete gradient ascent algorithm for logistic regression.
والآن لدينا لوغاريتم التدرج التصاعدي الكامل للانحدار اللوجستي.
Extremely simple, extremely useful and very cool.
الأمر بسيط للغاية، ومفيد جدًا وشديد الروعة.
So we're going to start from some point say, w0 and
حسنًا سنبدأ من نقطة ما لنقول w0
we're just going to follow the gradient here until we get to the optimal here,
وسنقوم باتباع التدرج الوارد هنا فحسب حتى نحصل على القيمة المثلى هنا
which we're gonmna and we're going to stop when the norm
وهي التي ستكون قيمة w hat وسنتوقف عندما يصبح معيار
of the gradient is sufficiently small with respect to tolerance parameter.
التدرج صغير بشكل كافٍ بالنسبة إلى متغير التفاوت.
Epsilon, like we discussed in the regression case.
إبسيلون، مثلما ناقشناه في حالة الانحدار.
And every time we take an iteration, we go feature by feature or
وفي كل مرة نأخذ تكرار، ننطلق خاصية بخاصية أو
coefficient by coefficient compute that partial derivative,
معامل بمعامل ونحسب ذلك المشتق الجزئي،
which is back to coefficient j.
الذي يعود إلى المعامل j.
So what is the derivative with respect coefficient and
لذا هو المشتق بالنسبة إلى المعامل
then we just update the coefficient by wj(t+1)
ثم نحدث المعامل من خلال wj(t+1)
by wjt plus the stub size times this derivative that we just computed.
من خلال wjt زائد حجم النهج القصير ضرب هذا المشتق الذي قمنا بحسابه للتو.
So this is notation for the derivative l at t,
حسنًا يُعد هذا رمزًا للمشتق l عند t،
which respects the parameter wj.
الذي يتعلق بالمتغير wj.
And at the core of the derivative, the only little computation that we
وعند صميم المشتق، العملية الحسابية الصغيرة التي يتعين
have to do Is this one over here, which is computing the probability
علينا إجراؤها هي هذه الواردة هنا التي تحسب احتمال
that the data point has value plus one with the parameters wt.
أن تكون قيمة نقطة البيانات زائد 1 مع المتغيرين wt.
So, what's that equal to?
لذلك، ما الذي يساويه هذا؟
Well, this is just exactly the logistic regression model.
حسنًا، هذا هو نموذج الانحدار اللوجستي بالضبط فحسب.
So, I'm going to do a change of colors transformation here and
لذا، سأقوم بتغيير تحول الألوان هنا
just do this in blue so it will stand out.
وسأجري هذا باللون الأزرق حتى يكون بارزًا.
This last little bit is just one over 1+e to the -w,
يدوم هذا لبعض من الوقت، وهو واحد على 1+e إلى -w،
which is whatever it is at iteration t.
وهو أي ما يكون عند التكرار t.
Transpose a h(of xi).
تبديل موضع h(لـ xi).
So I just compute that prediction, whatever my model thinks.
لذلك أقوم فقط بحساب ذلك التوقع، حسبما يعتقد النموذج الخاص بي.
I subtract to the indicators this a positive example,
أطرح حتى مؤشرات أن هذا مثال موجب.
multiplied by the feature value and there you go.
مضروبة في قيمة الخاصية، وها نحن ذا.
Some more data points.
المزيد من نقاط البيانات.
Simple algorithm, really useful, really, really useful.
لوغاريتم بسيط، مفيد للغاية حقًا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]